



JOHANNES HOLMBERG

Front-end Web Developer Basel, Switzerland.

johannes@holmberg.io +41 (0)79 - 926 32 74 holmberg.io

You find my projects at holmberg.io/work

Summary

I've been working on the web for the last 8 years. My professional skills range from front and back-end development to design and project management. My day can include scoping a project, fixing a CSS issue on a site, designing an iOS application and developing a WordPress theme in PHP. My focus is on how to always create a delightful digital experience.

Skills

Web stack HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

W3C standards compliance
Responsive / Mobile first approach

jQuery, Angular, Knockout.js, React.js

JSON, XML, Bootstrap

Pre-processors: Sass, Less

Version control: Git, SVN

Build tools: Gulp, Grunt

Environments

.NET MVC - Visual Studio (C#)

PHP - WordPress CMS

Software

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch,

Microsoft Office

Languages

English (Professional)

Swedish (Native)
German (Elementary)

Process Scrum, Kanban

Education

2007-2010

Linnaeus University, Kalmar, Sweden

Bachelor's Degree, Web Development

Experience

2015-

Front-end Web Developer, Consultant - Basel, Switzerland

I'm working as an external consultant together with web agencies to design, develop and implement web user interfaces.

Involves for instance: Designing of iOS applications and websites, front-end development, WordPress integrations.

2013-2015

Production Manager, Osynlig AB – Stockholm, Sweden

Working as a technical team lead. Handling project management and the development process. Also collaborating with external companies on bigger projects. Creating responsive web solutions with clients like Adobe, Mio and Mid Sweden University. *Involves for instance: Designing interactive prototypes, implementing with HTML/CSS and JavaScript frameworks like Angular.*

"If I were to name but one thing that I know for sure would improve the process, as well as the outcome, of your digital project I would say: Get Johannes on the team. He is skillful, confident, dedicated and a high performer in every detail." – Liz Tencic

2012-2014

UX Designer, Comic Health (Startup) – Remote

Designing prototypes for a new online health care application.

Involves for instance: Creating rough mockups with Balsamiq, iterating them through user testing and then implementing the design in the web application with HTML/CSS. Working in a Ruby on Rails environment.

2011-2012

Web Designer, EF Education First - Lucerne, Switzerland

Working as a web designer with focus on front-end development. Creating responsive, mobile friendly websites and applications for the company. *Involves for instance: Designing a prototype in Photoshop, implementing it responsively with HTML/CSS and then work closely together with the engineers in a .NET environment.*

"Johannes has the unique talent of writing high quality code while also providing excellent best practices for user experience and UI concepts." – Sean McGonagle

2009-2011

Web Developer, Osynlig AB - Sundsvall, Sweden

Creating WordPress themes and websites for clients all over Sweden.

Involves for instance: Converting a finished design into a WordPress theme and customize the CMS for the editors. Working heavily with PHP.